Guide to the James Ferlo Papers, 1963-2015 AIS.1998.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
James Ferlo Papers
1963-2015
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Ferlo, James (1951-2022)
AIS.1998.02
112.5 Linear Feet (90 boxes)
The James Ferlo Papers document the political career of James (Jim) Ferlo as a Pittsburgh City Councilman between 1987-2002 and as a Pennsylvania State Senator between 2003-2015.
Acquisition Information
Gift of James Ferlo.
Previous Citation
James Ferlo Papers, 1963-2002, AIS 1998.02, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Scope and Content Notes
The James Ferlo Papers document the political career of James (Jim) Ferlo, a Pittsburgh City Councilman between 1987 and 2002 and Pennsylvania State Senator between 2003-2015. The papers contain budgets, correspondence, legal materials, publications, reports, and other records related to Ferlo's legislative decision-making process as well as political issues in Pittsburgh and Pennsylvania during his terms.
Access Restrictions
Series I. Pittsburgh City Council, Subseries 11.
Arrangement
The James Ferlo Papers are arranged in two series:
Series I: Pittsburgh City Council Series documents Ferlo's career as a Pittsburgh City Councilman and is divided into eleven subseries: Alphabetical Subject File, City Council, City Departments, City Finances and Budgets, City Contracting and Legislation, Correspondence, Education, Election Materials, Issues File, Neighborhood Files, and Personnel Files.
Series II: Pennsylvania State Senate documents Ferlo's career as a Pennsylvania Senator and is divided into six subseries: Alphabetical Subject Files, Associations and Commissions, Legislation Issues and Correspondence, Job Recomendations and Requests and State Finances.
Biography
James (Jim) Ferlo (1951-2022) was born in Rome, New York, on June 19, 1951 to Thomas Henry and Isabella Ferlo. Running as a Democrat, he was elected to Pittsburgh's City Council in 1987 and served until 2002, representing the 7th District. He also served as City Council President from 1994 through 1997.
Ferlo served as State Senator in Pennsylvania between 2003 to 2015, representing the 38th District, which encompasses part of the city of Pittsburgh as well as surrounding municipalities in Allegheny and Westmoreland counties. He served as the Minority Chairman of the Senate Law and Justice Committee, Minority Vice Chairman of the Appropriations Committee, and a member of the Consumer Protection & Professional Licensure, Education, Finance standing committees, and the Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission. Ferlo came out as gay on September 23, 2014, thus becoming the Pennsylvania Senate's first openly gay legislator.
Ferlo has also been involved with many Pittsburgh organizations, including the Urban Redevelopment Authority (URA), the Green Ribbon Commission, the Joint Legislative Air and Water Pollution Control and Conservation Committee, Preservation Pennsylvania, and the Port of Pittsburgh Commission.
Education -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Pennsylvania -- Economic conditions; Pennsylvania -- Politics and government -- 1951-; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Economic conditions; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Commerce; Cable television -- Law and legislation -- Pennsylvania; Public utilities -- Law and legislation -- Pennsylvania; Correspondence; Personal papers; Politics; Government; Legislators -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Politics and government; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Officials and employees; Neighborhoods -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Economic development -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Economic development -- Pennsylvania; Public schools -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Pittsburgh (Pa.). City Planning Commission; Urban Redevelopment Authority of Pittsburgh; Pittsburgh (Pa.). Historic Review Commission; Pittsburgh (Pa.). Department of Public Works; Pittsburgh (Pa.). Department of Public Safety; Pittsburgh (Pa.). Bureau of Building Inspection; Pittsburgh (Pa.). City Council; Ferlo, James (1951-2022); Southwestern Pennsylvania Commission
- Pittsburgh City Council, 1963-2010; 1987-2002; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  The Pittsburgh City Council series contains eleven subseries, Alphabetical Subject File, City Council, City Departments, City Finances and Budgets, City Contracting and Legislation, Correspondence, Education, Election Materials, Issues File, Neighborhood Files, and Personnel Files. The records document James Ferlo's career as a City Councilman between 1987 and 2002 in Pittsburgh representing District 7. Materials include correspondence, lists, newsclippings, reports, and other records related to Ferlo's career and Pittsburgh politics during this period.
  - Alphabetical Subject Files, 1976-2003; 1987-2001; 1.
    The Alphabetical Subject File of the Pittsburgh City Council series contains Ferlo's alphabetical file of materials covering a variety of Pittsburgh-specific issues retained during his time as a councilman.
    - Accessibility, 1997-2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Adams, Harvey Lawsuit, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - ADEA- Mandatory Retirement Legislation, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - AFSCME Local 2719, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Agreement by/Amond Glass Plaza, Market View, and City of Pittsburgh, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Airport, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Alarm Fees, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Alcoa, Riverfront Development, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Alcosan, 1996-2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Allegheny Cemetery, 1988-2002 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Allegheny Conference on Community Development, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Allegheny General Hospital, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 11a)
    - Allegheny Regional Asset District, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Alternative Program Associates, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Amendments, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Amusement Tax, 1989-1999 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Animal Advocate Inc., 2002 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Animal Control, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Animal Control, 1989-1993 (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
    - Arc House, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Arch Court, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Arch Street, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Arsenal Park, 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Artwork, Brother Richard, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Amusement Arcade Legislation, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Ashland Spill, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Asphalt Plant, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Assessment Appeals, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Associations for Children and Adults with Learning Disabilities, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Ataleta, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Ater Way, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - AT&T Tower in Lincoln Larimar, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Auditorium Authority, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - AWWO, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - A1 Zoning- Change of Business Store Hours, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Auto Emissions Inspections Bill, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Aviary, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Bag-A-Thon, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Ballard Way, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Banks- PNC/First Federal Bank Merger, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Banner Permits, 1997-2002 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Bare Elegance, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - B-Contracts, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Beatty Club- 700 Block N, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Becks Run Rezoning, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Bedford Proposal, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Berman Site- 62nd Street, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Beverly, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Bicycle Police Patrol, 1989-1993 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Bigelow- 837 Highland Avenue, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Big Leagues, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Bike Helmets, 1994-1998 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Biking in the City, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Bingo, c1988 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Black Pittsburgh, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Block Watch, circa 1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bloomfield, Aloe Way, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Boat Ramps, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Bocce Court, Morningside, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Bottle Clubs, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Boundary Street, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Bowling, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Boys and Girls, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Braddock's Field, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Brereton Avenue, 1988-1994 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Brereton and 30th Street- Polish Hill Civic Association, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Brew House, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Bridges, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Briefing Book for Cooperative Services Program, 1993 December (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Broadhead Fording, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Brownfields, 1998-2000 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Bryant Street, 1989-1999 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Budget, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Buena Vista Social Club, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Buncher, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Bus Rerouting, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Business Privilege Tax, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Business Surveys, circa 1995 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Bussing Issues, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Budget and Summit Meeting Information, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Butler Street Fire, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Callowhill Street, 1995-1999 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Car Bash, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Car Lot Legislation, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Carnegie Library of Pittsburgh, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Carnegie Mellon University, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Carnegie Mellon University and Panther Hollow, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Carnegie Museum of Natural History, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Carrick Group Home, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Cash Machines, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Casino Theatre, circa 2000 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Catering, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Census, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Charlotte Street, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Chartiers Creek River Conservation, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Chatham College, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Childcare, 1990-1998 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Children's Festival, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Cigarette Vending Machines, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Ciotti Fence, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Citizen Participation, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - City Art Camp Program, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - City Controller "Tap in Fees", 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - City Pride Bakery, 1989-1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - City Used Furniture Inventory, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - City Wide Midget Football, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Civic Arena, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Civilian Police Review Board, 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
    - Civil Rights of the 1990s (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Clark, Brian, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Clark Candy, 1986-1995 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Clean City, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Clean Water Action, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Clemente Field, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - CMU Air Monitoring Station, Correspondence, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Coalition of Veteran's Advocates, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Co-Generation, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Coker Construction, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Collective Bargaining, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Colosimo, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Comedy Relief, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Commonwealth Warehouse Storage, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Community Advisory Boards, circa 1990 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Community Centers, Educational Facilities, and Religious Institutions, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Community Corrections Center #2- Pittsburgh Handbook, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Community Design, 1998-2001 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Community Enrichment Programs, 1996-2001 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Community Intensive Supervision Program (CISP), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Community Intensive Supervision Program (CISP), 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Community Policing, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Community Reinvestment Act, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Community Technical Assistance Center, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Complaints, 1993-1999 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Computer Labs, 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Concession Stand, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Concord Apartments, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Conrail, 1992-1997 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Constituent Complaints, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Consad, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Construction Junction, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Contractors' Licensure, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Convention Center, 1988-1995 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Cop Statistics, 1993-2002 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Corday Way Rezoning, 1994-1998 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Corrections, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Court Place, 1994-1999 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Craig House, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Credit Union, 1990-1996 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Crime Stoppers, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Crossing Guards, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Crosswalks, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Crown Property, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Cruising, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - CTAC Support Letters, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Congress Street, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Corporate Responsibility, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Cross Town Boulevard, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Cultural District, circa 1990 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Curfews, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 21-22)
    - Curfew Center, 1995-2001 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - D'Alessandro Funeral Home, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Dangerous Dogs, 1993-1996 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Databases, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Day Care Legislation, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Day of Caring, 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Dean's Field, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Deed Transfer Tax, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Defined Contribution, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Denny Parklet, 1995-2001 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Dental Assistance Fees, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Design Guidelines, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Deutschtown Historic District, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Development Fund Liquidation, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Development Models, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Development Projects, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Dinan Playground, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Diocese of Pittsburgh, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Disabilities Act, Pittsburgh Business Times, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Disparity Study, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - District Improvement Fund Information, 1999-2001 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Dithridge Street Cruising, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Dixon and Taylor St. Parking, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Dollar Bank, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Doughboy Square Firehouse, 1993-2000 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Downtown, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Downtown Bid, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Downtown Partnership, 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Downtown Plan, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Downtown Rezoning, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Downtown- Surface Parking Legislation and Appeal, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Downtown TIFF, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Drugs, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Drug Evictions, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Drug Policy, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Drug Task Force, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Duffield Street, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Dumping- Illegal and Rewards, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Dumping Surveillance, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Duncan Playground, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Dunster Street Development, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Duquesne Brewery, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Duquesne Incline, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Duquesne Light, 1987-1990 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Duquesne Light, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Duquesne Light Service Facility Closing, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Duquesne University Organizations, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - EEO, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - East Liberty Park / Darkins Park, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Economic Development, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - EMI Zoning Districts, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - A.G. Edwards, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Electric Choice, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Electronic Procurement, 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Eleventh Ward Committee, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - El Paso Street, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - EMS, 1997-2002 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - EMS Building, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Emergency Operation Center, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Emergency Shelter Grant, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Emergency Trust Fund, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Enrico's, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Enterprise Community Program, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Entertainment, 1986-2002 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Envirotest, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Environmental Legislation, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Equibank, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Ethics, 1989-1997 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Ethics Commission, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Exercise Warehouse Gym, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Exico, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Exxon Development, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Faces of Pittsburgh, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Fair Housing Act, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - False Alarms, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Family Entertainment Cetner, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Family Support, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - FAMIS System, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Farmers' Market, 1995-2002 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Farmhouse, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Federal American Properties, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Federal St. and North Avenue, 1989-1991 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Ferman Book, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Fencing for Fun, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Fields Steering Committee, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Fifth and Forbes, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Fifty-First Street Bus Shelter, 1989-1991 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Fifty-Seventh Street Ballfield, 1989-1992 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Film Industry, 1992-1998 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Financial Consultants, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Fiore Agreement, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Firearms- Prison, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Fire Department Reorganziation, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Firehouse Lawsuit, 1993-1995 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Fire Range, 1990-1992 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Fire Station Dispute, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Fire Stations, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Fire Study, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 19-20)
    - Fire Suit, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Fire Trucks, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Firefighter Pension Fund, 1994-2000 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Fisk Street, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Fleet, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Flu Vaccine Campaign, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Folk Music Festival, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Food Banks, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Forbes Field Task Force, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Forest City Station Square/ Lawrence Paint Building, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Forestry, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Fort Duquesne Blvd., 2000 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Fort Pitt Blvd., 2001 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Fort Pitt Bridge and Tunnel, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Fort Pitt Concession Stand, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Founders' Council, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Frank Curto Park, undated (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Fraternal Order of Police, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Freedom Corner, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Freeport Transfer Station, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Full Circle, 1992-1999 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Gallatin Street, 1998-2002 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Gangs, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Gang Summit, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Garbage, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Garbage Collection Tax, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Garbage Privitization, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - GASB 34 Project, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Gateway Pittsburgh, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - GBM, 1989-1993 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Gene Kelly Statue, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - General Services, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Gimbels, 2000-2002 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Golden Triangle Associates, 1989-1994 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Golf Course Taxes, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Good Government, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Goodwill Industries, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Graffam Building, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Graffiti, 1992-1995 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Graffiti Reward, 1992-1995 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Grand Prix and Vintage Grand Prix, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Grandview Hotel, 1990-1994 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Grant Case, 1991-1993 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Grant Street Lighting, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Greater Faith Tabernacle Church of God and Christ, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Greater Pittsburgh Convention and Visitors Bureau, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Green, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Green Neighborhood Initiative, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Greenways, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Grocery Item Pricing, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Gross, Lee, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Gross Street Development, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Guild Furniture, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Hall Family, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Halloween, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Halloween List and Letters, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Halloween Parade, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Halloween Parade-Lawrenceville, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Halloween Parade and Fright Night, October 1992 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Handicap Access Curbcuts/ Negley Commons, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Harkin, Tom (Senator), undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Harrison Street, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Hate Crimes, 1989-1999 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Hanlan Gregory Building, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Hatfield Street, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Hatfield Street (4901), 1992-1995 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Hazelwood Coke Plant (LTV), 1996-1998 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Health Proposals, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Haverhill Properties, 1991-1993 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Health Partnership, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Healthcare (Canadian System), 1992 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Healthcare (Indigent Care Plan), 1990 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Health Insurance (Blue Cross/Blue Shield), 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Health Service for the Disadvantaged, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Healthy Cities, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Heliport- Shadyside, 1988-1991 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Helistop- Shadyside, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Heppenstall's Site, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Heth's Playground, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Heth's Run Bridge, 1997-2000 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Highland Avenue Lighting Project, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Highland Building, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Highland Park Farmhouse, 1990-1995 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Highland Park Observatory, 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Highland Park (PAT Bus Problems), 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Highland Park Shooting Gallery, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Hillman Foundation Annual Report, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Historic Review Commission, 1993-2000 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Historic Preservation, 1992-1997 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - History, 1988-2000 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Homelessness, 1988-1991 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - HACP- Homeownership Program, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Home Rule Charter, 1974-1998 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Home Rule Charter Advisory Board, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Homestead Merger, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Home Value Guarantee, 1992-2001 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Homicide Task Force, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Hop Along, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Hope 6 Application, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Horoscope, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Hospitals, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 3)